<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The mournful widow, or, A full and true relation of the aparition [sic] in Baldwins Garden being an account of the walking-spirit of Mr. Thomas Cooke, sometime stone-cutter in Baldwin's Gardens, deceased. As it was taken from the widow of the said Mr. Cooke; and several other persons (some of which were divines of the Church of England) that were eye and ear-witnesses of the prodigious appearances, and actions of the deceased Mr. Cook. Published at the request of some relations, and particular friends; to prevent, if possible, the false reports, that have been, or may be industriously spread by ignorant or prejudiced persons.</title>
            <author>Cooke, Elizabeth.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 14 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B02371</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C6007A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R176382</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52612105</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52612105</idno>
            <idno type="VID">179386</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B02371)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 179386)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2787:1)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The mournful widow, or, A full and true relation of the aparition [sic] in Baldwins Garden being an account of the walking-spirit of Mr. Thomas Cooke, sometime stone-cutter in Baldwin's Gardens, deceased. As it was taken from the widow of the said Mr. Cooke; and several other persons (some of which were divines of the Church of England) that were eye and ear-witnesses of the prodigious appearances, and actions of the deceased Mr. Cook. Published at the request of some relations, and particular friends; to prevent, if possible, the false reports, that have been, or may be industriously spread by ignorant or prejudiced persons.</title>
                  <author>Cooke, Elizabeth.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by J. W. near the Green Dragon Tavern in Fleet-Street,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: blurred print, tightly bound with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Cooke, Thomas.</term>
               <term>Ghosts --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:179386:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE <hi>Mournful VVidow,</hi> OR, A full and true RELATION OF THE APARITION IN Baldwin<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Garden BEING An Account of the Walking-Spirit OF Mr. <hi>THOMAS COOKE,</hi> Sometime A <hi>Stone-Cutter</hi> in <hi>Baldwin</hi>'s-<hi>Gardens,</hi> Deceaſed.</p>
            <p>As it was taken from the <hi>Widow</hi> of the ſaid <hi>Mr. Cooke;</hi> and ſeveral other Perſons (ſome of which were Divines of the Church of <hi>England</hi>) that were Eye and Ear-VVitneſſes of the prodigious Appearances, and Actions of the Deceaſed <hi>Mr. Cook.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ubliſhed at the Requeſt of ſome Relations, and particular Friends; to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent, if poſſible, the falſe Reports, that have been, or may be induſtriouſly ſpread by Ignorant or Prejudiced Perſons.</p>
            <p>Licenſed and Entered according to Order.</p>
            <p>Printed by <hi>J. W.</hi> near the <hi>Green Dragon tavern</hi> in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet,</hi> 1690.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:179386:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:179386:2"/>
            <head>The Mournful Widow: Or, a Full and True Relation of the Aparition in <hi>Bald<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>win's Gardens.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>IT has been the opinion of ſome people, as well Divines as as others, that there are no ſuch things as Spirits, Appa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rations, Daemons Viſible and the like; but that all the af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frightments of Men and Women proceeding from the ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed ſight of the aforeſaid Objects, are no more or other than the pure effects of prejudic'd fancy, weakneſs of Heart, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It is the deſign therefore of this paper, to convince the incre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulity of theſe Atheiſtically principlied perſons, (as I may juſtly call them) (ſince they are oppoſite to expreſs Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, and try'd Experience) by an inſtance of this nature which is ſo far from being ſeigned or falſe, that there can be ſome ſcores of eye and ear-witneſſes to be produc'd, who will upon any occaſion atteſt the reality of this ſubſequent Relati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and all this too not to be enqu red after, or left in doubt by diſtance of place, or other difficulties, ſince the Circumſtan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces and thing it ſelf may be prov'd in this very City; and though the modeſt gravity, and indeed, ſorrow of the Wife and Relations of the Deceaſed (whom we will preſently name) has put a ſtop to any particular publication of the enſuing paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſages, yet ſince ſhe has by malicious Tongues been cenſur'd as contributing, if not cauſing the Melancholly Diſſatisfacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of her Husband aforeſaid, ſhe cannot be diſpleaſed in hearing her own Vindication, and expoſing the plain matter of fact according to the truth declared by ſeveral of her own Family, as well as confirm'd by her ſorrowful ſelf: Which is as followeth. <hi>Thomas Cook</hi> by Trade a Stone-cutter, living be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tween <hi>Grays-Inn-Lane</hi> and <hi>Leather-Lane,</hi> had lived with hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Wife <hi>Elizabeth Cooke</hi> for many years, during which time he ha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> (being in himſelf of a ſurly nature) many bickering proceed<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:179386:3"/> chiefly from his ill Husbandry, he indeed working pr<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>b<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>d hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſelf, but would upon the receipt of his Money, t<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> little or no care of his Family; So that his two Children a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Wife had wholly their own Subſiſtance from the Wives o<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Induſtry, who was by Trade a Body's-Maker, while he wou<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> be drinking out his daily gettings, and indeed, not witho<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> ſhrewd Suſpicion of keeping bad Women company: Howe<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ver, nothing of ſuch moment (as can be poſſibly gather'd fro<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> any of his Family) in the whole time they lived together, h<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ned, as to make any Impreſſion or Diſſatisfaction more th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> ordinary, indeed he had by his laviſh Expences, brough<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> himſelf to ſuch Inconveniences, that occaſioned him during t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> whole tearm of their living together, to be Arreſted thir<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> times, and he as often experimented the pious fondneſs of h<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Wife, in being every time reliev'd and ranſom'd by her pecu<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>liar Charge and Induſtry: So that the Malicious and baſe Scan<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dals raiſed by ignorant People, or prejudic'd Heads, are who<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ly confuted and evinc'd, ſome of which pretend that Jealou<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> cauſed his Melancholy, and that he ſhould ſuſpect the fidelit<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of his good Wife, whoſe Honeſty and Virtue has been in <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> her Neighbourhood, both approv'd and applauded; others i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>pute the diſturbance of his Spirit, to his having left ſever<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Sums of Money hid and conceal'd; but this from the ver<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> meaneſt of his Circumſtances in the World is invalied; and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſpeak truth, neither his Wife, nor any of his Family ca<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> give the leaſt probable reaſon for this Diſturbance he puts them too, except it be, that his Heart being ſo hardned by the Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lurements, Inſtigation and Temptation of the Devil, that though on his ſick Bed, (which moſt commonly renders the Conſciences and Actions of evil-Livers in viſible and mournful Characters) he could not heartily ſet himſelf to ſuch a ſincere Sorrow, Grief and Repentance for his Sins, as was requiſite, or that the Subtilty of the Devil made them ſo black and nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merous before him, that he wholy deſpaired of God Almigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> infinite Mercy, and the effectual Mediation and Merits of his only Son our moſt Bleſſed Saviour, and ſo left the World
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:179386:3"/> in a ſort of Grudging and Grief, as may very pr<gap reason="illegible" extent="5 letters">
                  <desc>•••••</desc>
               </gap>ly <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> prov'd from ſeveral Expreſſions that dropt from him during his Sickneſs, eſpecially towards the latter end: For his good Wife during his Sickneſs, (which laſted a whole week and no more, and began with a ſort of troubleſome Hickup,) his good Wife I ſay, being willing and ready to take care for the future wellfare of his Soul, as well as for the preſent eaſe and amendment of his Body; would frequently kneel down and pray heartily by him, at ſome of which times, he would ſhew himſelf very devour, and bear a part in her pious Eja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culations, as once he cry'd out to her after ſhe had been zea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>louſly praying: Ah! Dear Wife, doubtleſs the good and great God will have reſpect to the fervend Sincerity of thy Prayers; <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd I and my Family ſhall fare the better for them, at ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther time he was wholy deſperate, and in a great agony Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claimed: Ah! tis too late, too late, you and I my Dear, you and I have a greater Account than this to reckon for, thus would he vary, and turn between Hope and Deſpair; and to <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he laſt, expreſt himſelf as Doubtful and Fearful, that he <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hould not obtain God Almighty's Mercy and Forgiveneſs of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>is Sins, and in that Condition dy'd about the ſixth or ſeventh <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ay after his firſt Ill-neſs: And now the Diſconſolate Widow <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>aving Diſcharged a good Conſcience in a ſtrict care, and Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>iful Attendance of her Husband living, was thinking of a Modeſt and Decent Diſpoſal of his Corps now Dead, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ordingly had him Interr'd with all the Circumſtances uſual <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd proper; but to her great Amazement, was ſcarce well re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>urnd from his Buryal to her own Houſe, when there was <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eard a great clattering noiſe as the falling of Pewter or Shelves, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o that the VVidow thinking the VVine-Veſſel and other things <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y the careleſſneſs of the Maid was fallen down, was juſt upon chiding, till upon a Search, they found all things in their <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ight order, to their great Aſtoniſhment: The fourth night al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>er his Burial about M<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>dnight, they heard a great tumbling <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>f Stones, and pecking as if ſome body had been at work in <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Shop; But that which made the VVidow believe it, a
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:179386:4"/> Daemon or Spirit was the inſenſible moving a Stone from one place to another, as he us'd often when alive, alſo ſhe would hear the very noiſe of cutting of Stones under her Bed, and ſometimes would perceive the Bed while ſhe was lying in it, hoi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſted up in a ſtrange manner. About a week after his Buryal, the Maid who lay in a little Room by her Miſtreſs, perceiv'd her Feet of a ſudden to be preſs'd down, as if ſome heavy bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>then had been thrown down upon her, and the next Morn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing her Feet were ſeen very ſore, ſwell'd, and Black, and her ſelf extreamly Affrighted.</p>
            <p>Another time, the Nurſe, that ſat up with the Widow, went into the little Room to waſh her Hands, the Maid being in Bed, who lay as in a Trance, her Eyes being open, and fixt upon one place, all in a Sweat, her Hair ſtanding up, at which the Nurſe in a great Fright left the Room, and ſhutting the Door, immediately heard ſomething Jump, as it were, heavily from the Feet of the Maids Bed, and walk along the Room; then the Nurſe took Heart, and went to the Door and harkned, and ſhe perceiv'd ſomething move up to the Door, and lean'd it ſelf in a poſture of hearkning too. By this time the Maid was come to her ſelf, and call'd to th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Nurſe, who after ſome time came, to whom ſhe told wha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Miſery ſhe had ſuffer'd; and Ask'd, <hi>If ſhe had not heard a ſa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Groaning all the Night?</hi> As alſo, <hi>That her Maſter came ſo nea<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> her, that her Breath was almoſt ſtopt.</hi> Before Nurſe could ge<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> back, it was got under the Widows Bed; who calling for he<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Prayer-Book, and recommending her ſelf to the Great God Protection, ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e boldly call'd out, in the Name of the Father Son, and Holy Ghoſt, <hi>What ar<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Thou that thus do'ſt troutle us. And what wouldſt Thou have?</hi> whereupon it flung open th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Curtains furiouſly, and giving a great Stamp, went down in to the Shop, and was there heard Pecking, as when Alive on the Stones. Five or Six Gentlemen being deſirous to b<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſatisfied of the truth and meaning of this Apparition; ſom<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> being of Opinion, there was no ſuch thing; coming thith<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> merrily together, one of them belonging to <hi>Gray's-Inn,</hi> of
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:179386:4"/> ſudden Crys out, in a Fright, <hi>Here he is;</hi> at which the other <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>miling, as if he had Jeaſted on purpoſe to ſcare them, he ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ouſly told them, and pointed to him, drawing the Curtains of the Bed, which they all heard, but ſaw not. He alſo <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>aid, He was in Black Cloaths, with a Muſling-Nckcloth tied <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ith a Black Ribbon, and was at the Beds-feet, and inclining <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o a poſture of Kneeling; but as ſoon as the Gentleman aroſe <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rom his Seat, it vaniſhed, and began its uſual Frolick of Pecking Stones. Sometimes while the Nurſe and the Widow <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ave lain together, it has lifted up the Bed, ſo that they have <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>een in danger of falling out. One time in his own real ſhape <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> appear'd to a Stone-Cutter, his old Acquaintance, and with <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>bundance of Threats and Menaces, charg'd him to repay the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ixteen Shillings he had receiv'd of his Wife for his Grave<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>tone. Another time, about Twelve of the Clock at Night, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e appear'd to the Watch who were going by his Houſe. A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother time, the Widow and her Family ſitting up till near One of the Clock, and frequently falling to Prayers, of a <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>udden they perceiv'd the Candle burn Blew, and preſently <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eard a great Knocking, the uſual warning that he gives of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>is Approach, and being worn out with tedious Watching, ſhe <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ell into a gentle Slumber, when the Young Woman that lay <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ith her fell a Crying, <hi>Oh Miſtreſs, your Pillow is on Fire;</hi> at which ſhe wak'd, and felt one ſide of her Head very ſore, as <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>f it had been ſcorch'd or bruiſed; and looking out on the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>loor by her Miſtreſſes ſide, <hi>She ſaw a Fire riſing up like a Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ar, and more than the compaſs of a Peck;</hi> then the Widow Cry'd out, <hi>Avoid Satan, my Truſt is in God;</hi> and ſtrait the Fire went to the other ſide of the Bed and vaniſht; and preſently <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>fter, they could ſee the full proportion of the Deceaſed in <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>his Crape-Burial-Dreſs, and croſſing the Room, diſappear'd. Two Young Men that lie in the ſame Houſe, <hi>Saw one Night <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he full ſhape and proportion of a Man lying all along by their Bed ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>de, and falling Zealouſly to their Prayers, he ſtarts up, and with <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n Angry Frown leaves them:</hi> Another time, the ſame Two Young Men going out late one Night, it being very Dark,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:179386:5"/> they were ſcarce got out of the Gate, <hi>But a great Light aro<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> a ſudden, and moving towards them, they could perceive ſomet<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> as it were a Dog coming up to them; and preſently it took ſome of Monſtrous Shape, which they could not diſtinguiſh, and preſe<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> whirling by them it vaniſht, and left them in great Terrour a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Darkneſs again.</hi> Three Young VVomen ſitting up with t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> VVidow, about Eleven of the Clock there was a great Blo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> given in the little Room, where the Maid us'd to lie, and Noiſe as of ſome Body walking too and fro, and then th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> all counted ſeveral diſtinct Knocks, to the Number of Twe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ty. One of the VVomen that ſat nigh that Room Door, b<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing Curious to Peep, was thrown by an inſenſible force out <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> her Chair; and it ſeem'd to her, as if it had been ſome ſtron<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Blaſt of VVind. At Seven of the Clock, by the ſame inviſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ble force, the ſame Young VVoman was terribly ſhaken i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> her Chair. Laſt <hi>Sunday</hi> Night Two other VVatchmen com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing along by the Houſe, called at the <hi>Hole</hi> in the <hi>Wall</hi> to Drink, and ſeeing a Man ſtand hard by, went up to him and Asking who he was, he ſt<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ait diſappear'd. Theſe an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> many other prodigious Diſturbances of the like nature do al<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>moſt happen every Day and Night in the Houſe of the ſai<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Cook,</hi> lately Deceaſed, to the wonderful Aſtoniſhment of a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> that hear it, and Terrour of thoſe poor VVretches that hav<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſeen and felt many of them And becauſe the Truth of eve<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ry Circumſtance here related may be juſtly Vindicated, any Perſon that deſires farther ſatisfaction, may receive it fully from the Mouths of Hundreds in <hi>Baldwin's-Gardens,</hi> or from the VVidow of the ſaid <hi>Cook,</hi> who with her whole Family have ſadly Experimented the Reality of this Relation.</p>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
